# **Aminu Rabiu**

## WEB DEVELOPER

**SUMMARY** 

A passionate and enthusiastic Software Developer with 2+ years of experience working with React and Rails. Previous accomplishments include slashing downtime by 25% and ensuring 98% on-time project completion. An empathetic team player and mentor and an innovative, creative thinker.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Upwork Remote

Freelance Web Developer | August 2022 - Present

- Integrating third-party APIs and tools to enhance software functionality and increase SEO by 40%.
- Building strong client relationships by providing excellent customer service to 100 to over 100 customers daily.
- Demonstrating proficiency in various software development methodologies, such as Agile and Scrum, to enhance project management and collaboration efficiency by 30%

Full Stack Software Developer, Remote **Student** | June 2022 – Present

- Conducted regular code reviews and provided constructive feedback to at least 40 people per day, leading to improved code quality and team collaboration.
- Recruited, trained, and managed a team of over 40 people, using agile development methodologies, including Scrum and Kanban.

# **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE | August 2022 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

ALX SE | June 2022 - Present

Remote Full Stack Software Engineering Program, Full Time

• Spent a year in supervised learning, working with various languages and frameworks related to Software Engineering.

Portfolio URL | Github Linkedin | Medium arabiu033@gmail.com

## **SKILLS**

**Front-End**: JavaScript, TypeScript, React/Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Python, C, NodeJS, Express, LoopBack, GraphQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Bash, Vagrant

**Professional**: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

# Highlighted Personal Projects

#### Shell

- This is a UNIX command interpreter based on bash and Sh.
- Built with (C Language)

#### **Countries API**

- This API integration project displays a list of countries and their information.
- Built with (HTML, CSS, and Javascript)

#### **PodCast**

- A simple pod request accessing the Landing page.
- Built with (HTML, CSS, and Javascript)

# Ahmadu Bello University

# BSc, Mechanical Engineering (In Progress), expected graduation date Dec @2023

- Developed Strong work ethics, analytical thinking, and problem-solving abilities in a fast-paced environment.
- Won exceptional merited awards from both national and private bodies. This is due to the academic excellence I demonstrated.